If we are interested in looking at the relationship between two quantitative variables,
如果我们想研究两个数值变量之间的关系
the go-to plot type is the scatter plot.
那就选散点图
In a scatter plot, the values of one variable are indicated by position on
散点图的 x 轴表示一个变量的值
the x-axis and values of the other variable are indicated by position on the y-axis.
y 轴则表示另一个变量的值
One point is plotted for every observation we
图表中的每个点都代表了
have in our data resulting in a cloud of points.
数据中的一个观察值 最终形成了点群
The pattern of points can clearly show what kind of
点群的分布模式明确地体现了
relationship exists between our two variables and its strength.
两个变量的相关性 以及相关性的强度
We are often interested in quantifying the strength of
通常我们会把两个变量的相关性强度量化
the relationship between two variables through a correlation coefficient.
用相关系数来表示
The most commonly used measure is the Pearson correlation coefficient,
最常见的相关系数是皮尔逊相关系数
identified by the letter r. A detailed discussion of
以字母 r 表示 虽然要细讲这个相关系数
this correlation coefficient is best left for
最好另开一节课
a different course but a quick overview is worthwhile here.
但我觉得有必要在这里稍微介绍一下
The statistic takes a value between negative one and one.
这个系数的值在 -1 和 1 之间
Positive numbers indicate relationship where positive changes in
当系数为正时
one variable are associated with positive changes in the second.
一个变量发生正向变化 另一个变量也会发生正向变化
While negative numbers indicate that when one variable increases,
当系数为负时
the second variable tends to decrease.
一个变量增加 另一个变量就会减少
Values close to the extremes of negative one or one indicate a stronger,
系数接近 1 或 - 1 时 变量相关性更强、更容易预测
more predictable relationship while values close to zero indicate a weaker relationship.
系数越接近 0 变量关系则越弱
The correlation coefficient does not necessarily tell you anything
相关系数未必能告诉你
about the steepness of a line that models the relationship.
拟合线的斜率
And most importantly,
而且最重要的是
the Pearson correlation coefficient only captures linear relationships.
皮尔逊相关系数只能表示线性关系
As observed with Anscombe's quartet,
如果观察安斯库姆四重奏数据
we had multiple data sets with the same Pearson correlation coefficient,
我们会发现 虽然这些数据集的皮尔逊相关系数相同
but when plotted demonstrated very different shape characteristics.
但是这些数据的图像形状有明显差异
It is important to consider not just the numbers
所以你不仅要考虑数字本身
alone but whether or not they are meaningful for your data.
还要考虑这些数字是否对你的数据的意义
If one of our goals is to create a regression model around the data,
如果我们想创建数据的回归模型
scale transformations can be useful to change a non-linear trend in
对于自然单位下呈非线性趋势的数据 可以采用标尺变换
the natural units into a linear trend in the transformed units.
使变换后的数据呈现出线性趋势
Let's say that we have a scatter plot like the one shown.
假设我们手里的散点图是这样的
As we increase the value of x,
随着 x 值增加
the spread in the value of y increases drastically.
y 值的涨幅会越来越大
If we change the scaling of the y variable to a log scale,
如果将 y 变量的标尺改为对数标尺
then a linear pattern appears.
线性模式就出现了
This informs us that we want to try using the value of
这就意味着在回归时
x to predict the log of y in a regression approach.
我们要用 x 的值来预测 y 的对数值